## **Alex Wang**

## Auckland, Auckland 1026 ♦ 02102510440 ♦ swoecwang10@gmail.com

## **Summary**

I have 12 years of hands-on development and testing experience with a Bachelors degree in Computer Systems Engineering. I enjoy keeping up with new tools, creating and testing code is my passion. I've been involved on 12 commercial projects since 2006.

## Skill set

- ✓ Full-Stack Java and Python Development
- ✓ Requirements analysis
- Automated testing
- ✓ System&Database design
- ✓ Web Service design and implementation (REST/SOAP)
- ✓ Microservices
- ✓ Android development

## SKILLS AND METHODOLOGIES

- ✓ Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, BootStrap, JavaScript, Ajax, Jquery, AngularJS, JSP
- ✓ Back-end: SpringMVC, SpringBoot, JPA Hibernate, Mybatis, JDBC, Struts, Shiro, WSDL, Swing, Rest&SOAP, NodeJS
- ✓ Database: Oracle, Mysql, MongoDB, Sqlite, Sql server
- ✓ MQ&Distributing system: MQTT, Kafka, Hbase, Hadoop, Cloud storage
- ✓ Search engine: Lucene, Elasticsearch
- ✓ Python: Spiders, Machine learning, Django
- ✓ Automatic Testing: TDD, BDD, Cucumber, Selenium, Behave, Mockito, Stub, Apprium, TestNG, Junit, Findbugs, Coverage, Testrail, Mocha, Chai
- ✓ Server: Docker, Kubernetes, Tomcat, Redis, Nginx, Image, FTP, Weblogic, IIS, Jboss
- ✓ Design: Powerdesign, Axure RP, UML, Dia
- CI&CD: Git, SVN, Jira, Maven, Jenkins, Bitbucket, Swagger, Ant, Grunt, Smoke testing, Intergation testing, System testing, Driving testing
- ✓ Methodology: Agile
- ✓ System: Linux, Linux Kernel
- ✓ IDE: Eclipse, IDEA, Anaconda, Webstorm
- ✓ Android: 3Y+ experiences
- ✓ E-Commerce

## **Experience**

## Software developer XM developments 08/2018 Auckland

XM developments is a company working on e-commerce system and online stores

The e-commerce platform is based on Java8, Jpa, spring-boot, Elasticsearch, Redis, test using behave, cucumber, Junit, Testrail, Git, Bitbucket, as well as Docker, Kubernetes.

- ✓ Developed new features for user groups: designed and added new columns to the database(flyaway), upgrade models, and relative functions. developed test cases and tested the new features(behave in python and Junit)
- ✓ Labels setting block: designed the label setting tables, designed the Rest APIs, developed all the functions (service, JPA, flyway)
- ✓ Junit test and Functional test
- Designed database
- ✓ Designed Rest APIs
- ✓ Code Review
- ✓ Code refactoring

**Team Leader & architect** senior engineer Ligoo New Resource Co, LTD 02/2016-03/2018 Hefei Ligoo New Resource is the second largest company building BMS for the electric vehicle as well as diverse services in China.

- ✓ Designed web Framework (Spring)
- Developed upgrade system by using message queue (MQTT)
- ✓ Maintained the platform and delivery servers (Ubuntu)
- Analysis the data by using python
- Designed and built the development environment and architecture
- ✓ Implemented core business services
- ✓ Lead the development of the online platform
- ✓ Performed code reviews
- Designed and developed components(Front-end & Back-end)
- ✓ Addressed and fixed bugs
- √ Cooperated with test and operational engineers to optimize business services
- Developed an Android APP for a logistics system
- Developed a search engine by using Elasticsearch
- Developed a pipeline by using Kafka
- Developed spiders to grab data from Internet with Python
- ✓ Junit Test, Functional Test, Driving Test
- ✓ Requirements analysis
- ✓ Saved significant costs (at least \$2M every year) to maintain numerous users and respond quickly to users' complaints
- Attracted larger user base as the system helped customers monitor their vehicles' status

# Senior Software engineer Aisainfo-inc Global Delivery Service 06/2014—01/2016 Nanjing one of largest CRM software supplier in the world (NASDAQ: ASIA)

- Developed functions for Nepal Telecoms, such as balance system, booking system, clients
  Package system
- √ (Front-end & Back-end)
- Clarified meta-data and optimized the system structure(Oracle)
- ✓ Developed plug-ins
- ✓ Reacted with web interfaces
- ✓ Fixed bugs and maintained the system
- Developed workflows
- ✓ Junit Test Integration Test
- ✓ Support diverse demands from the users
- ✓ Continuous integration and delivery when whatever happens(even a big earthquake)

## Senior Software engineer CITIC Department of venture Control 06/2012-06/2014 Nanjing

CITIC corp is the largest financial company in China and top 500 companies in the world.

- ✓ Designed customized blocks
- Developed features for Audit platform(Front-end & Back-end)
- Data transferring
- ✓ Junit and functional test
- ✓ Integration & System Test and Delivery
- Developed APPs for Bank in Android
- ✓ Improve the service quality 200%
- ✓ Better resource relocation
- Saving money as more as 20 thousand dollars every year for every branch(more than 500 branches)

## Architect Compal R&D center 06/2010-2012 Nanjing

second-largest contract laptop manufacturer in the world, also top 500 companies in the world, headquarters is in Taipei, Taiwan, with offices in the People's Republic of China, South Korea, the United Kingdom and the United States

- Refactored our android systems
- ✓ Designed system structure
- ✓ Developed new features
- ✓ Interacted with external web interfaces
- Designed and Developed web interfaces
- ✓ Developed a search engine(Lucene)
- Codes became the assets

#### Senior. Software Engineer ZTE 06/2008-05/2010 Nanjing

The fourth Largest mobile equipment manufacturer in the world, with offices in 180 countries.

- ✓ Mainly developed FAC and FAS, using multi-thread, and IPC, message-queue, pre-read for cloud storage system
- ✓ Tested and analyzed the bugs
- ✓ Optimized the system
- ✓ Wrote reports to compare our product with several other cloud products
- ✓ Sold billions of US dollars every year
- ✓ Supplies services for Italy telecom, Vietnam telecom, China Telecom, and many other countries.

### Software Engineer Inspur 06/2006-06/2008 Nanjing

one of the largest solution provider in the world

- ✓ Developed the core block for SIP(Java Web project)
- ✓ Designed and Developed new layers for map(Java Swing)
- Designed and Developed new layers for map(Java Swing)
  Developed super-large search trees(more than 100,000 points)
  Developed themes and search functions by using swing
  Junit and Functional test
  Code review

- ✓ Fixed bugs
- √ 12600 times faster by using multithread to get massive data

### **EDUCATION & REFERENCES**

Computer Science Shandong University 2002 / IBM DB2 International Certified (2006)

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

## **OTHER**

Github: https://www.github.com/swoec

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-wang-63237b39/